<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>🗞 Posts on </title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 🗞 Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The myths of marble, glass and blood: A sociological analysis of Monument Mythos</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/the-myths-of-marble-glass-and-blood-a-sociological-analysis-of-monument-mythos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/the-myths-of-marble-glass-and-blood-a-sociological-analysis-of-monument-mythos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The place where critical thinking is subversive</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I introduced myself in my last post. I&amp;rsquo;m a 14-year-old teenager from Brazil, and I wanted to write down some thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve had about politics — and just some thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve had about the world. In particular, my experience with “gringos” (mostly Americans), their school system compared to ours, and how interacting with and discovering the Anglophonic side of the internet changed my entire worldview.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always heard adults make remarks like: “This country is doomed forever!” or “We&amp;rsquo;re not nearly as civilized as America!” or even “Our educational system is a mess! I wish I could study in the United States.” Those remarks made me picture the United States as one of the most advanced developed countries, and mine as doomed to forever be an undeveloped hellhole.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Socio-Political aspect of Frutiger Aero</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/fa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/fa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the design language and pseudo-artistic movement known as “Frutiger Aero” has resurfaced on platforms like TikTok, often through glossy ecological CGI images accompanied by captions such as “This was the future we were promised.” These posts collectively point to a single idea: Capitalism used to be optimistic. This optimism isn&amp;rsquo;t common even when compared to past Western design languages such as Memphis and Y2K, which also featured futuristic imagery but differ from Frutiger Aero in the use of ecological, skeuomorphic, and optimistic imagery allied to the new translucent effects that CGI could generate. Today, however, it is rare to find new products, interfaces, or artistic expressions by major corporations that follow its aesthetic principles. This raises the question: Why did it vanish?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
