<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>🗞 Posts on Bear Cub</title>
    <link>http://localhost:40505/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 🗞 Posts on Bear Cub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt-BR</language>
    <managingEditor>helloimmiguel@yahoo.com (Miguel)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>helloimmiguel@yahoo.com (Miguel)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Miguel @ The Afterthought Space (Copyleft) 2025</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:40505/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The myths of marble, glass and blood: A sociological analysis of Monument Mythos [EN]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:40505/blog/the-myths-of-marble-glass-and-blood-a-sociological-analysis-of-monument-mythos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>helloimmiguel@yahoo.com (Miguel)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:40505/blog/the-myths-of-marble-glass-and-blood-a-sociological-analysis-of-monument-mythos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;body&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  “THE TREE OF LIBERTY MUST BE REFRESHED FROM TIME TO TIME WITH THE BLOOD OF PATRIOTS AND TYRANTS.”&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is what Thomas Jefferson once said in the universe of Monument Mythos: an analog horror ARG about lovecraftian monsters that come out of the American monuments that metaphorically exist in our reality and are fed with millions of innocent people every single day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Why do we build monuments?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We build them to remember, they say; however, we actually build them to forget. Quoting the Polish sociologist Lech Nijakowski (2006), monuments do not merely commemorate the past; they actively claim territory and impose meaning. In a summary, they are built not just to commemorate the past but to commemorate and weaponize one past; &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; past. They mythologize and exaggerate a nationalist vision of a past that reduces history and its complexities into pride and enforce a hegemonic narrative of a chosen, liberated people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<body>
<blockquote>
  “THE TREE OF LIBERTY MUST BE REFRESHED FROM TIME TO TIME WITH THE BLOOD OF PATRIOTS AND TYRANTS.”
</blockquote>
<p>This is what Thomas Jefferson once said in the universe of Monument Mythos: an analog horror ARG about lovecraftian monsters that come out of the American monuments that metaphorically exist in our reality and are fed with millions of innocent people every single day.</p>
<h1>Why do we build monuments?</h1>
<p>We build them to remember, they say; however, we actually build them to forget. Quoting the Polish sociologist Lech Nijakowski (2006), monuments do not merely commemorate the past; they actively claim territory and impose meaning. In a summary, they are built not just to commemorate the past but to commemorate and weaponize one past; <em>their</em> past. They mythologize and exaggerate a nationalist vision of a past that reduces history and its complexities into pride and enforce a hegemonic narrative of a chosen, liberated people.</p>
<p>But beneath this shiny marble pride lies a machinery of death: a great meat grinder of workers dying for their homeland, killing for their “people,” when in truth, the only ones pulling the trigger are the merchant and the banker.</p>
<p><strong>Monument Mythos</strong>, and in special, the episode <strong>LIBERTYLURKER</strong> makes it grotesquely literal. The Statue of Liberty in their universe, as well as several other monuments worldwide, shelters an otherworldly lovecraftian creature named "Special Tree" that's fed with some visitors and in special was fed with entire families of Italian immigrants who arrived in New York in 1954 after fleeing poverty and seeking liberty and were diverted to Ellis Island to be fed to the monster kept by America as a promise of power.</p>
<p>This not only makes literal the abstraction of monuments as agents to build nationalism but also demonstrates the immigration question in the US: poor people fleeing war, persecution and misery that find a meat grinder beneath the symbol of liberty they seek.</p>
<p><em>As a footnote</em>, I'd like to present the recent news that The Department of Homeland Security is considering taking part in a television show that would have immigrants go through a series of challenges in Ellis Island to get American citizenship. The challenges would be based on various American traditions and customs, said Tricia McLaughlin, a spokeswoman for the agency. This is a self-explanatory oddly laughable way of highlighting the question with the immigrants that I just went on.</p>
<h2>The working class's degradation kink: the glorified agents of the bourgeoisie as working-class pop divas</h2>
<p>In the episode <strong>"DEANDEMOCRACY"</strong> and throughout President Dean's term in Monument Mythos, we're shown that James Dean, a 60s famous actor that died in a car crash, actually ran for presidency and won. The episode that made him popular enough to win by a landslide was an announcement by ABC News that they'd broadcast something of national importance in the following day, which was a 30-second ad for Dean that made the entire American population, including his adversary Nixon, crazy for him.</p>
<p>In the following years of his term, he lobbied for a computer company responsible for ending the world and was posed as the savior of America after supposedly disabling siren broadcasts that made the population deaf and distributing hearing aids.</p>
<p>This highlights a present issue in not just America but any country with a strong influence of the mediatic and industrial bourgeoisie: the corruption of democratic institutions. We regularly see candidates for public power being supported by the ruling class to eventually lobby for them as presidents or congressmen.</p>
<p>Marx (1875) understood that what liberalism calls “democracy” is merely a temporary form of class domination; a bourgeois democracy, meant to delay the revolutionary rupture.</p>
<p>All of this happens while the working class fights each other and tears itself apart for the Blue, White or Red parties; as if their misery had a favorite color... Meanwhile, the real war; the one between labor and capital, stays offstage, hidden behind patriotic jingles and the glow of national monuments.</p>
<h2>The Anomalous Economy: Historical Materialism in a World of Monsters</h2>
<p>Throughout the series, we see that the material base of the world economy is different from ours — but not really. We see elements such as Giza Glass, a mythological kind of glass formed in the Egyptian desert and kept as a secret of the Bedouin tribes, being exploited and robbed from their homeland to behead people in order to make them slaves.</p>
<p>This can be interpreted as a metaphor for the insatiable need of capitalism to beastialize people with gizmos produced or originated from the Global South. Quoting President J. D. Rockefeller’s line in <strong>ROCKEFELLERREVELATION</strong>: <q>Crowns are incapable of forming unions.</q></p>
<p>This symbolic economy of monsters and divine artifacts is, in essence, not anomalous or fictional at all; it is merely capitalism dressed in myth. Giza Glass is not glass; it is rubber, cobalt, lithium, oil. Crowns aren't beheaded slaves; they are the sweat of the alienated American middle class and African child labor sold as divine providence.</p>
<h2>Myth as Weapon: The Aestheticization of Politics</h2>
<p>Fascism, said Walter Benjamin, is the aestheticization of politics. In the universe of Monument Mythos, this becomes literal.</p>
<p>The Statue of Liberty doesn't shelter an otherworldly meat-loving creature. There isn't a big Horned Serpent lying in American territory that destroys the world circa 2022. There's no ADA, no Maize Machines and no Virginia Arnoldson. The entire narrative structure works not to expose the violence of the bourgeois state, but to decorate it — with marble, with gold, with myth, with horror wrapped in velvet.</p>
<p>This is the same mechanism we see in the real world, albeit in less theatrical form. In the series <strong>Severance (2022)</strong>, corporate alienation is turned into a metaphysical drama: workers surgically separated from their own lives, identities split in two, truth buried in smiling HR seminars and productivity slogans.</p>
<h2>Final Act: When the curtain falls</h2>
<p><strong>Monument Mythos</strong> is not just an alternate history. It is an ideological machine dressed as art — and like every monument, it asks not to be understood, but worshipped. As long as we aestheticize politics without exposing its class roots, we are feeding the Special Tree or buying Lumon's lies.</p>
<p>We are silencing the miners, the mothers, the children in foreign wars. We are swallowing a myth built to keep us docile marching in circles while the same hands profit from our steps. <strong>But myths can be rewritten. And monuments, when pulled down, become bricks.</strong></p>
</body>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The place where critical thinking is subversive [EN]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:40505/blog/ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>helloimmiguel@yahoo.com (Miguel)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:40505/blog/ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I introduced myself in my last post. I&amp;rsquo;m a 14-year-old teenager from Brazil, and I wanted to write down some thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve had about politics — and just some thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve had about the world. In particular, my experience with “gringos” (mostly Americans), their school system compared to ours, and how interacting with and discovering the Anglophonic side of the internet changed my entire worldview.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always heard adults make remarks like: “This country is doomed forever!” or “We&amp;rsquo;re not nearly as civilized as America!” or even “Our educational system is a mess! I wish I could study in the United States.” Those remarks made me picture the United States as one of the most advanced developed countries, and mine as doomed to forever be an undeveloped hellhole.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>I don&rsquo;t think I introduced myself in my last post. I&rsquo;m a 14-year-old teenager from Brazil, and I wanted to write down some thoughts I&rsquo;ve had about politics — and just some thoughts I&rsquo;ve had about the world. In particular, my experience with “gringos” (mostly Americans), their school system compared to ours, and how interacting with and discovering the Anglophonic side of the internet changed my entire worldview.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always heard adults make remarks like: “This country is doomed forever!” or “We&rsquo;re not nearly as civilized as America!” or even “Our educational system is a mess! I wish I could study in the United States.” Those remarks made me picture the United States as one of the most advanced developed countries, and mine as doomed to forever be an undeveloped hellhole.</p>
<p>This began to change when I started interacting with the Anglosphere on the web, learning English in the process. Eventually, I downloaded apps like Discord and Reddit and began interacting and learning more about their culture. But I was pretty young, so I didn’t really focus on that. Since last year, though, I&rsquo;ve been increasingly bothered by their culture, which I started learning more about as I got a friend group on Discord with mostly Americans and Western Europeans.</p>
<h2 id="how-i-became-the-">How I Became the 🤓</h2>
<p>Since the beginning of March this year, an unexpected cultural jolt hit me hard. My friend group — originally formed through Nintendo Homebrew shenanigans — started to evolve. We gradually drifted away from tech talk and began sharing more about our personal lives. At the same time, I was undergoing a major shift myself: I started getting deeply interested in books, philosophy, politics, MUNs, and history — things outside the standard school curriculum. This is pretty normal for someone entering high school, as you begin making decisions that can shape your future. But to my surprise, that shift started to upset them. Whenever I brought up anything related to reading, studying, or politics, I was hit with the classic 🤓 — not offensive in itself, but what followed was.</p>
<h2 id="overfunded-undereducated--the-contradiction-of-the-american-school">Overfunded, Undereducated — The Contradiction of the American School</h2>
<p>When I brought up school, they usually shared their own experiences too. Not only that, but I also began to stumble upon — and be constantly fed by — content about American education during my daily doomscrolling sessions.</p>
<p>The biggest contradiction to me was their entire vision of school: why they were there, what they thought of their teachers, staff, and the institution as a whole. They seemed to see school not as a space for learning or development, but as a burdensome, bureaucratic hurdle — just something to endure in order to eventually get into college. They don’t see teachers as anything more than servants who are there purely to do their job — meanwhile here, we call them “Uncle/Auntie” as if they were part of our family, and we treat the ones we like as friends and sometimes even add them and talk to them on Insta — and they call that weird or even pedophilic.</p>
<p>Some of them, directly or indirectly, despise their school staff and do acts of vandalism that I simply cannot comprehend — for example, the F Student trend, which consists of teenagers either burning their school laptops or shoving them down a toilet. Meanwhile, even in private schools here, it’s rare to see schools that give laptops to kids, and it’s simply nonexistent in public ones. Not to mention the hassle that their janitors go through while cleaning that kind of mess — which can even be hazardous. Their daily job already seems really difficult when I hear how they leave their classrooms and food courts.</p>
<p>This all sums up to: how can you hate school when your school looks like a college campus? Brazil spends approximately $4,306 yearly per full-time student, but even elite private high schools cost around $7,000 yearly per student, compared to the $11,000 that OECD countries spend on average — and the $15,591 that the U.S. spends on average. However, even considering the reality of public schools, it seems like we have a way more advanced curriculum than the U.S. Our SAT equivalent, the ENEM, doesn’t allow the use of calculators or any kind of aid during the test, yet it has much harder questions. It expects not only operational fluency, but contextual interpretation, abstraction, and problem-solving — even if wrapped in wordy, socially-relevant questions. In the ENEM, you might find a question that requires manipulating complex numbers, understanding the imaginary unit i, or even applying it to a real-world context like electrical engineering or waves. In the SAT? You’re more likely to be penalized for even attempting to use i unless the question specifically tells you it’s allowed. And even then, the scope is laughably basic — usually limited to “What is i²?” or “Simplify (2 + 3i)(1 − i).” Things that basically any mediocre 10th grader in Brazil could answer. I learned the basics of square roots in 5th grade and learned how to solve any by factoring in 8th; meanwhile, if they aren&rsquo;t “math wizards,” they couldn&rsquo;t figure out the cube root of 64 without a calculator if their life depended on it.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not even going to scratch the surface on linguistics, humanities, or natural sciences, because the contrast becomes even more absurd. While my country constantly devalues education through underfunding, it still manages to uphold a curriculum that treats these areas as essential to forming a citizen — not just a worker. Meanwhile, many of the people I’ve met online see these fields as useless unless they provide immediate financial return. Their schools often treat subjects like history, philosophy, sociology, or even environmental science as electives or filler. Sometimes, even teachers actively discourage deeper engagement, pushing students to focus only on what’ll be on standardized tests. It’s a culture where the only kind of knowledge worth pursuing is the one that yields capital — and where not knowing becomes almost a point of pride.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>How can you cultivate critical thinking in a place where asking questions is seen as being “too political”?</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="reading-is-suspicious-and-politics-is-a-symptom">Reading is Suspicious, and Politics is a Symptom</h2>
<p>The moment I really realised how deep the cultural canyon ran was when I mentioned I was reading for fun. It wasn’t even a complex book by Dostoevsky or Kafka — just some guy who became paraplegic because he fractured his spine by diving into a lake and wrote a book about it while high on THC — suddenly I’m being called the “nerd,” the “try-hard,” the “pseudo-intellectual.” I wasn’t even trying to show off — I was trying to connect. I’m not going to lie and say reading is common here, because it’s not — however, the core difference is that no one despises it or despises the people who read. They admire them.</p>
<p>For most of them, books were a thing of the past, or a thing you were forced to pretend to care about for school essays. Reading for leisure was strange, and worse: reading political theory? Dangerous. When I started talking more seriously about politics — not even anything radical — I was labelled paranoid, brainwashed, or “too young to have opinions.” In their world, caring is suspicious. Thinking critically is overstepping. And talking politics, especially outside the approved script of “Democrats = good, Republicans = evil,” is treated like raging schizophrenia and equated to people who say the earth is flat and 9/11 didn’t happen.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, I come from a country where everyone has an opinion on politics — because we’re forced to. We grow up watching corruption scandals unfold on the evening news, we have our grandparents giving us unintentional sociology lectures at family lunch, and we learn to distrust the system not because it’s fashionable, but because it’s a matter of survival. Our political consciousness isn’t an aesthetic — it’s how we cope. We tend not to be so nihilistic and say “nothing will change” because we saw it change. My mother saw the first time her grandpa, born in the 30s, voted. She remembers the day our constitution was signed, the day people were no longer tortured for having an opinion, and the day being racist and homophobic became a crime.</p>
<h2 id="am-i-in-the-third-world-or-are-they">Am I in the Third World or Are They?</h2>
<p>After all this, I often wonder: am I really the one living in a “third world country,” or are they? On paper, the U.S. has an incredible school system and funding that’s higher than the OECD average, which enables school districts to build schools with pools, gigantic multi-sport courts, gyms, updated tech equipment, etc. But what I’ve witnessed is the complete opposite of what that suggests — and not because of their organization or funding; the culprit is the culture. Students who sabotage their own learning out of boredom or rebellion. A culture that shames intellectual curiosity instead of nurturing it. An environment where caring too much or thinking too deeply is mocked or seen as a mental illness.</p>
<p>Not to mention what comes after school — undervalued community college that’s relatively affordable but still costs money, or endless student debt even for public colleges. I think honestly the thing that confused me the most was how I met someone who’s paying way more than any med student in Brazil possibly could in a private college — which by definition should be funded by the taxes they already pay — and they are, in most sane countries. But instead, that money goes to bombing brown children in the Middle East because of oil and endless military lobbying.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in Brazil, despite the countless flaws in our education system — overcrowded classrooms, violence, lack of funding, outdated or nonexistent materials, and the current attempt by neoliberal state governors to underfund schools and devalue school staff even more — there is still a respect and admiration for knowledge, a respect for teachers, and a shared understanding of the importance of education as a tool for socio-economic change. My mom is the vice-principal of the afternoon period of a public school, and I can guarantee that if any of those kids were given a laptop for school, they would protect it with their lives — same for any kind of public property that’s not usually given to them.</p>
<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>I don’t claim to have all the answers. Our education system is deeply flawed — both in public and private schools. It suffers from inequality, prejudice, underfunding, and a near-total neglect of neurodiversity. And yes, our culture has its own contradictions: not everyone is politically engaged, not everyone reads regularly, and not everyone respects teachers or public property. But here’s the crucial difference — we see these problems. We talk about them. They’re not swept under the rug or dismissed as unimportant.</p>
<p>There’s a sense, however faint, that we’re moving forward — through activism, through collective pressure, through small victories in policy and public awareness. We recognize where we’ve failed, and that self-awareness is what makes transformation possible. We may be limping toward a better future, but at least we’re walking.</p>
<p>In contrast, what scares me most about the culture I witnessed isn’t the lack of engagement — it’s the pride in disengagement. The hostility toward curiosity. The glorification of comfort over truth. It’s hard to change what you refuse to admit is broken.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Socio-Political aspect of Frutiger Aero [EN]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:40505/blog/fa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>helloimmiguel@yahoo.com (Miguel)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:40505/blog/fa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the design language and pseudo-artistic movement known as “Frutiger Aero” has resurfaced on platforms like TikTok, often through glossy ecological CGI images accompanied by captions such as “This was the future we were promised.” These posts collectively point to a single idea: Capitalism used to be optimistic. This optimism isn&amp;rsquo;t common even when compared to past Western design languages such as Memphis and Y2K, which also featured futuristic imagery but differ from Frutiger Aero in the use of ecological, skeuomorphic, and optimistic imagery allied to the new translucent effects that CGI could generate. Today, however, it is rare to find new products, interfaces, or artistic expressions by major corporations that follow its aesthetic principles. This raises the question: Why did it vanish?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nowadays, the design language and pseudo-artistic movement known as “Frutiger Aero” has resurfaced on platforms like TikTok, often through glossy ecological CGI images accompanied by captions such as “This was the future we were promised.” These posts collectively point to a single idea: Capitalism used to be optimistic. This optimism isn&rsquo;t common even when compared to past Western design languages such as Memphis and Y2K, which also featured futuristic imagery but differ from Frutiger Aero in the use of ecological, skeuomorphic, and optimistic imagery allied to the new translucent effects that CGI could generate. Today, however, it is rare to find new products, interfaces, or artistic expressions by major corporations that follow its aesthetic principles. This raises the question: Why did it vanish?</p>
<p>It faded not merely due to stylistic obsolescence, but because it reveals deeper socio-political dynamics that are obsolete and impractical nowadays. Through a historical materialist lens, Frutiger Aero can be interpreted as part of the superstructure — a reflection and reinforcement of the economic base of mid-2000s global capitalism, particularly as neoliberalism advanced across both the Global North and Global South (MARX, 1859). It emerged during a time of global economic expansion after the Dot-Com Bubble and during the logistical revolution with the internet and higher-capacity faster cargo airplanes that were reshaping the means of production throughout the world and, with that, the introduction of a new international division of labor — which posed the Global South not just as a source of raw material but also as a source of cheap labor for industrial work that First-World countries and their citizens did not want to do (MARX; ENGELS, 1848).</p>
<p>According to Marxist theory, this shift in the core of the global economy needed an ideological superstructure to obscure its contradictions and legitimize its consequences (ENGELS, 1893). Under these circumstances, the technological and media bourgeoisie tailored a new design language and pseudo-art movement that would be optimistic and ecological to mask real social contradictions — growing inequality, ecological destruction, war — under a veneer of harmony and fluidity, promoting a vision of capitalism not only as efficient but as benevolent: a form of ideological mystification (GUEVARA, 1965). The high-gloss water droplets, blue skies, and leaves suggest environmentalism — but only as a corporate commodity, not a material critique; this aligns with commodity fetishism, where the image of “green tech” or a “clean future” distracts from the exploitative labor and environmental costs behind the scenes (MAO, 1942).</p>
<p>Fredric Jameson’s concept of “cognitive mapping” is useful here: Frutiger Aero acts as a visual and ideological tool to help consumers navigate the abstract complexities of late capitalism, simplifying contradictions into easily digestible, optimistic imagery (JAMESON, 1991). Guy Debord’s notion of the “society of the spectacle” also applies — the glossy aesthetics function as a spectacle that masks social relations and alienation, turning consumption into a quasi-religious experience (DEBORD, 1967). Mark Fisher’s ideas on capitalist realism help explain why this aesthetic became obsolete: when capitalism’s failures become undeniable, such optimistic visions feel increasingly hollow and ironic, no longer able to sustain the fantasy of a benevolent future (FISHER, 2009).</p>
<p>In short, Frutiger Aero communicated:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The future is now. We’re saving the environment. Sit down, consume, and watch the skylines rise.”</p></blockquote>
<p>All while such promises were materially impossible under capitalism, whose logic is built on an insurmountable contradiction: infinite growth on a finite planet (ALLENDE, 1972).</p>
<p>The user-friendly, clean interface becomes the new factory floor — a space of consumption disguised as empowerment. The aesthetic functioned ideologically, persuading the working class and emerging middle class that consumption itself was an act of ecological progress. Capitalism’s survival depends on presenting itself as inevitable and benevolent, and Frutiger Aero was its glossy disguise to push the working class to consume. It appealed to the rising middle working class and the lower bourgeoisie — aspirational, professional, mobile — promising access to a “global” modernity suggesting a detached, frictionless life, available only to those with purchasing power. The poor, exploited, and excluded are never represented in this aesthetic as if they were not the ones supporting the system — the ones building the glassy skyline on a burning sun while the happy family sits and has a picnic using some 2000s gizmo — much like they are erased from liberal-capitalist narratives.</p>
<p>The decline of Frutiger Aero is rooted in a broader cultural shift. In an era marked by climate collapse, economic precarity, neo-fascist politics, and erosion of institutional trust, the promises embedded in this aesthetic ring hollow. The same corporations that once branded themselves with ecological optimism — Google’s “Don’t be evil,” for example — have become synonymous with surveillance capitalism and exploitation. We simply cannot buy it anymore because it’s too cynical for the present day. Companies are investing either in neo-brutalist design, such as Google’s Material 3, that communicates “The world is confusing and unfair, and we’re not going to sugarcoat it,” or are returning to glossy and translucent aesthetics analogous to their past eco-centered counterparts to appeal to Gen Z and Millennials, as Apple and Microsoft have done recently with Windows 11 and the rumored design for iOS 19.</p>
<p>In summary, Frutiger Aero represents the socio-political landscape of the 2000s, marked by emerging ecological problems and technological advances. It can be seen through historical-dialectical materialism as the optimistic smokescreen launched by the bourgeoisie to back increasing consumeristic trends and persuade the proletariat to blind themselves to the obvious unsolvable contradictions of capitalism and its newly introduced global neoliberal experiment. It was never meant to be real — just a fever dream living on a slightly scratched Galaxy Tab discarded by an American middle-class family, now polluting an e-waste site in Ghana and posing hazards to human and wildlife and leaking chemicals into the soil like it&rsquo;s ideology once did to our people.</p>
<h1 id="references">References</h1>
<p>ALLENDE, Salvador.
Speech at the United Nations General Assembly. 1972. Available at: <a href="https://www.marxists.org/archive/allende/1972/december/04.htm">https://www.marxists.org/archive/allende/1972/december/04.htm</a>. Accessed on: May 17, 2025.</p>
<p>DEBORD, Guy.
The Society of the Spectacle. Detroit: Black &amp; Red, 1967.</p>
<p>FISHER, Mark.
Capitalist Realism: Is There No Alternative? Winchester: Zero Books, 2009.</p>
<p>GUEVARA, Ernesto Che.
Man and Socialism in Cuba. 1965. Available at: <a href="https://www.marxists.org/archive/guevara/1965/03/man-socialism.htm">https://www.marxists.org/archive/guevara/1965/03/man-socialism.htm</a>. Accessed on: May 17, 2025.</p>
<p>JAMESON, Fredric.
Cognitive Mapping. In: The Ideologies of Theory: Essays 1971-1986. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press, 1991.</p>
<p>MAO ZEDONG.
Talks at the Yenan Forum on Literature and Art. 1942. Available at: <a href="https://www.marxists.org/reference/archive/mao/selected-works/volume-3/mswv3_08.htm">https://www.marxists.org/reference/archive/mao/selected-works/volume-3/mswv3_08.htm</a>. Accessed on: May 17, 2025.</p>
<p>MARX, Karl.
Preface to A Contribution to the Critique of Political Economy. 1859. Available at: <a href="https://www.marxists.org/archive/marx/works/1859/critique-pol-economy/preface.htm">https://www.marxists.org/archive/marx/works/1859/critique-pol-economy/preface.htm</a>. Accessed on: May 17, 2025.</p>
<p>MARX, Karl; ENGELS, Friedrich.
The Communist Manifesto. London: Penguin Classics, 2002.</p>
<p>ENGELS, Friedrich.
Letter to Franz Mehring, 1893. Available at: <a href="https://www.marxists.org/archive/marx/works/1893/letters/93_07_14.htm">https://www.marxists.org/archive/marx/works/1893/letters/93_07_14.htm</a>. Accessed on: May 17, 2025.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
